# Nikhil Kotha



nkotha90@gmail.com



919666694333

# CAREER OBJECTIVE

Hard-working professional with 9+ years of experience and a proven knowledge of client relationship management, key account management & contract negotiation. Aiming to leverage my skills to successfully assist in achieving the Mission of the Organization.

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

Comprehensive experience and a significant level of success in handling top executives, development of marketing material, scheduling and budgeting. Recognized as a creative and practical problem solver with an ability to manage multiple tasks all in time-critical, fast-paced and high-volume settings. Exceptional communicator with demonstrated success in building and maintaining relationships with upper management and key corporate decision makers. Ability to adapt quickly to challenges and changing environments. Recognized as a good team leader and player, quick learner, capable of adapting to a variety of contexts and people. Enthusiastic, self-motivated and willing to assume increased responsibility.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Institute of Hotel Management, Hyderabad - July 2008 - May 2011 Bachelor of Science (Hospitality and Hotel Administration)** 

- Achieved All India Rank of 782(top 4%) in the entrance test for hospitality that focused for aptitude for customer service.
- 6 Months industrial training across various hotel departments at Taj Krishna, Hyderabad and was a key performer in all the various departments.
- Participated in the PATA Event Executive Training Program conducted at NITHM from 23.08.08 01.09.08.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Prakara (BVR Projects Pvt LTD), Telangana / February 2022 - Present - Sales Head - India

- To Tie up with Institutional Organizations to onboard them for using our application.
- To Tie up with B2B organizations located Pan India.
- To Target B2C vertical with the use of digital platforms to expand the customer base.

# United Network India (Ram Info Limited), Telangana / August 2020 - Jan 2022 - Sales Head - India

- To Tie up with Corporate Companies for Logistic Needs all over India.
- To expand business operations in East and West parts of India.
- To handle a team of Business Development Managers based out of all the Metro Cities.

### Park Hyatt, Hyderabad, Telangana / Oct 2017 - Sep 2019 - Associate Director of Sales

- Leading the team of 4 people and ensuring that the hotels budgets are met in all segments along with the team members individual budgets.
- Responsible for closure of IPL Business at the hotel for 2018 and 2019 estimated to 3Cr Revenue per year.
- Responsible for driving Corporate and MICE Business from feeder markets such as Mumbai and Pune for the unit.
- Plan and direct staffing, training, and performance evaluations to develop and control sales and service programs.
- Review operational records and reports to project sales and determine profitability.
- Prepare budgets & targets for the hotel on monthly basis for the Team basis past and future trends.
- Plan Aggressive Strategies with proven ability to close deals via strong and persuasive closing skills.

#### ITC Kakatiya, Hyderabad, Telangana / Sep 2015 - Oct 2017 - MICE Manager

- Responsible for handling all MICE Queries at the unit.
- To mainly coordinate with the Events & Revenue Team to understand on the availability and send out quotations across for all MICE Queries.
- Handling of Sports Segment at the Unit ( Key Contributor being BCCI and IPL ).
- Achieved 95% budget for MICE Segment, 90% budget for Corporate Segment and 105% budget for banquet sales in the year 2016-17.
- Responsible for handling feeder markets of Mumbai and Chennai for the unit.

# Marriott Hotels, Hyderabad, Telangana / May 2014 - Sep 2015 - Assistant Sales Manager - Reactive Team

- Responsible for handling feeder market queries from Mumbai and Delhi.
- Responsible for handling the PSU Sector for the hotel and handling all MICE and Corporate Queries.
- Responsible for handling the Social and Weddings Portfolio for the unit with a budget of 6 Cr.

#### Lodha Group, Hyderabad, Telangana / Feb 2012 - Apr 2013 - Dy. Sales Executive

- Responsible for handling Sales for the Premium Property Lodha Bellezza and achieved budget by 95% with a revenue of 20Cr.
- Responsible for handling the Channel Partners( Real Estate Agents) Sector and drive business for the unit.

- Responsible for handling the Loyalty Program to gather references and generate new business for all three Properties (Lodha Bellezza, Lodha Meridian and Lodha Cassa Paradisso) located in Hyderabad.
- Responsible for driving key sales in Pre-Launch & Launch phase of Lodha Meridian estimated to 80Crs.\

# **ADDITIONAL SKILLS**

English - Business Level Speaking, Reading and Writing Been a Leader in the Inter – Departmental Activities involving Inter-Club Sports , Theme Based Cuisines ,etc Experience of developing, executing and managing various successful events. Attend industry related seminars to follow latest market trends.

# REFERENCES

References available upon request